<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>

	<!-- EN: mousekin -->
	<Mousekin_XenotypeMousekin.label>Mousekin</Mousekin_XenotypeMousekin.label>
	
	<!-- EN: Species: &lt;i&gt;Mus sapiens albus&lt;/i&gt; ("Wise white mouse")\n\nA race of small and agile anthropomorphic mice, readily identified by their large round ears, short-snouted faces, black beady eyes, pink noses, slight overbite, thin scaly tails and white fur.\n\nMousekin adult males can grow up to 100 centimeters tall, while females tend to reach 90 centimeters in height. They have a smaller head-to-body ratio compared with other humanoid races, resembling oversized toddlers with short legs and noticeable hind rumps.\n\nThe average gestation period is similar to baseline humans, after which an pregnant mother would typically give birth to a single pup; twins, triplets and other multiple births are rare.\n\nVariations among individual Mousekin include different head hair color and lengths independent of their white body fur, as well as moustaches and other forms of facial hair for males.\n\nWhile the vast majority of humanoid rodent-like races in the galaxy are the product of deliberate genetic experimentation on baseline humans dating back millenia, it is generally understood that Mousekins are among the very few species that have evolved naturally from their non-sapient mouse ancestors.\n\nBarring accidents, injury or disease, a Mousekin’s average life expectancy is 90~100 years; their head hair turns fully grey by around 60 years of age, but no Mousekin will experience baldness. -->
	<Mousekin_XenotypeMousekin.description>Espécie: Mus sapiens albus ("Rato Branco Sábio")\n\nUma raça de pequenos ratos antropomórficos ágeis, reconhecíveis pelas grandes orelhas redondas, focinho curto, olhos pretos brilhantes, narizes rosados, leve sobressaliência dentária, caudas finas e pelagem branca.\n\nMachos adultos alcançam até 100 cm e fêmeas cerca de 90 cm. Têm proporção cabeça-corpo menor que outros humanóides, lembrando crianças grandes de pernas curtas e traseiro proeminente.\n\nA gestação é semelhante à humana, resultando normalmente em um único filhote; múltiplos são raros.\n\nVariações entre Mousekins incluem cor e comprimento do cabelo na cabeça, independentes da pelagem, e bigodes ou barba em machos.\n\nEmbora a maioria das raças roedoras humanoides tenha origem em experimentos genéticos antigos, acredita-se que os Mousekin evoluíram naturalmente de ancestrais não sencientes.\n\nExceto em caso de acidentes, ferimentos ou doenças, a expectativa média de vida de um Mousekin é de 90~100 anos.\n\nSem acidentes ou doenças, vivem em média 90–100 anos; o cabelo fica grisalho por volta dos 60, mas nunca ficam carecas.</Mousekin_XenotypeMousekin.description>
	
	<!-- EN: A naturally-evolved Mousekin with no major significant genetic modifications. -->
	<Mousekin_XenotypeMousekin.descriptionShort>Um Mousekin naturalmente evoluído, sem grandes modificações genéticas significativas.</Mousekin_XenotypeMousekin.descriptionShort>

	<!-- EN: Grimalkin -->
	<Grimalkin_XenotypeGrimalkin.label>Grimalkin</Grimalkin_XenotypeGrimalkin.label>
	
	<!-- EN: Species: &lt;i&gt;Felis sapiens atratus&lt;/i&gt; ("Wise black cat")\n\nA race of large anthropomorphic cats, readily identified by their triangular ears, uniformly dull black fur, yellow slit-pupiled eyes, protruding upper incisors and long bushy tails.\n\nGrimalkin adults can grow up to 150 centimeters tall, with males and females possessing visible scrotums and subdued chest mammary glands respectively, while individuals are discerned by subtle variations in head fur swirl or body odor. Their anatomical proportions are roughly similar to domesticated cats from Old Earth, save for additional bulk from body hair and fat.\n\nThe average gestation period is similar to baseline humans, after which an pregnant mother would typically give birth to a single kitten, but twins, triplets and other multiple births are also possible.\n\nWhile the vast majority of humanoid feline races in the galaxy are the product of deliberate genetic experimentation on baseline humans dating back millenia, it is understood that Grimalkins originated from pet cats abandoned by an Old Earth Asian rump superpower's failed attempt at interstellar colonization; environmental and evolutionary pressures accelerated the species’ rise into sapience within a span of a mere few hundred years.\n\nBarring accidents, injury or disease, a Grimalkin’s average life expectancy is 70~80 years; their body fur becomes slightly matted by around over 60 years of age, but no Grimalkin will experience fur loss. -->
	<Grimalkin_XenotypeGrimalkin.description>Espécie: &lt;i&gt;Felis sapiens atratus&lt;/i&gt; ("Gato preto sábio")\n\nUma raça de grandes gatos antropomórficos, facilmente identificáveis pelas suas orelhas triangulares, pelagem preta uniforme e opaca, olhos amarelos com pupilas fendidas, incisivos superiores salientes e caudas longas e espessas.\n\nOs adultos Grimalkin podem crescer até 150 centímetros de altura, com machos e fêmeas possuindo escrotos visíveis e glândulas mamárias suaves no peito, respectivamente, enquanto os indivíduos são diferenciados por variações sutis no redemoinho do pelo da cabeça ou no odor corporal. Suas proporções anatômicas são aproximadamente semelhantes às dos gatos domesticados da Velha Terra, exceto pelo volume adicional do pelo corporal e da gordura.\n\nO período médio de gestação é semelhante ao dos humanos comuns, após o qual uma mãe grávida normalmente daria à luz um único filhote, mas gêmeos, trigêmeos e outros nascimentos múltiplos também são possíveis.\n\nEmbora a grande maioria das raças felinas humanóides na galáxia seja produto de experimentos genéticos deliberados em humanos comuns que remontam a milênios, entende-se que os Grimalkins se originaram de gatos de estimação abandonados por uma tentativa fracassada de colonização interestelar de uma superpotência asiática da Velha Terra; pressões ambientais e evolutivas aceleraram o surgimento da espécie em sabedoria em um período de apenas algumas centenas de anos.\n\nExceto em casos de acidentes, ferimentos ou doenças, a expectativa de vida média de um Grimalkin é de 70 a 80 anos; seus pelos ficam ligeiramente emaranhados por volta dos 60 anos de idade, mas nenhum Grimalkin sofre perda de pelos.</Grimalkin_XenotypeGrimalkin.description>
	
	<!-- EN: A naturally-evolved Grimalkin with no major significant genetic modifications. -->
	<Grimalkin_XenotypeGrimalkin.descriptionShort>Um Grimalkin que evoluiu naturalmente, sem modificações genéticas significativas.</Grimalkin_XenotypeGrimalkin.descriptionShort>
	
</LanguageData>