<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Defs>

	<IdeoStoryPatternDef Name="Mousekin_IdeoStoryPatternDefBase" Abstract="True">
		<segments>
			<li>description</li>
		</segments>
	</IdeoStoryPatternDef>

	<IdeoStoryPatternDef ParentName="Mousekin_IdeoStoryPatternDefBase">
		<defName>Mousekin_IdeoDesc_Kingdom</defName>
		<rules>
			<rulesStrings>
				<li>description->In ages past, mice once squabbled over berries, nuts and fertile mouse maidens, their uncivilized ways blighting the land. Through the teachings of [deity0_name] and his thirteen disciples, we came to honor our forefathers for bestowing us the gift of life by keeping our flesh and spirits pure, and to venerate the meadows and forests that nourish us. For those that heed the wisdom of [deity0_name] are rewarded with everlasting life in The Great Garden, while the deviants and the wicked shall wander The Wasteland forevermore.</li>
			</rulesStrings>
		</rules>
	</IdeoStoryPatternDef>
	
	<IdeoStoryPatternDef ParentName="Mousekin_IdeoStoryPatternDefBase">
		<defName>Mousekin_IdeoDesc_IndyTown</defName>
		<rules>
			<rulesStrings>
				<li>description->For generations, our ancestors toiled in the fields and mines of the Kingdom, chafing under the heavy taxes levied by nobles. The mice of the woods, moved by our plight, shared a feast of vension poached from the King's own forests, while teaching us the ways of brotherhood and equality. Inspired by their generosity and wisdom, we turned our backs on those who would exploit us for their own gain, and built a society where every mouse could squeak their mind and enjoy the fair fruits of their own labors.</li>
			</rulesStrings>
		</rules>
	</IdeoStoryPatternDef>
	
	<IdeoStoryPatternDef ParentName="Mousekin_IdeoStoryPatternDefBase">
		<defName>Mousekin_IdeoDesc_Nomad</defName>
		<rules>
			<rulesStrings>
				<li>description->Just as our ancestors once roamed the meadows and forests for sustenance, we too wander in search of spritiual succor and beauty. For change is the only constant, and to remain is to stagnate.\n\nThis is the Way.</li>
			</rulesStrings>
		</rules>
	</IdeoStoryPatternDef>
	
	<IdeoStoryPatternDef ParentName="Mousekin_IdeoStoryPatternDefBase">
		<defName>Mousekin_IdeoDesc_Brigand</defName>
		<rules>
			<rulesStrings>
				<li>description->"My nuts! Mine, all mine!"\n\n  - Castor Gnawtooth, while picking through his spoils</li>
			</rulesStrings>
		</rules>
	</IdeoStoryPatternDef>


</Defs>